<archimate:BusinessProcess
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Verify Open Source Software Ownership or Licence"
    id="737a343d-0f2f-435b-a407-94c79d4d8b6f"
    documentation="Whenever the Crown is contemplating acquiring software under an open source licence, departments should review the terms and conditions to validate if they can accept and comply with them given their particular business context.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The software is usually provided ‘as-is’ meaning the community will not accept liability or provide any financial compensation to the Crown for service interruption, loss of data, or loss of confidentiality. As such, you should consider the software obtained under an OSS licence with the same responsibility lenses as if you had written it.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;All software licensed under an Open Source Initiative approved license or a Free Software Foundation free software licence is considered open source software and, where its use is possible in accordance with this Guide, can be used by the GC without modifications.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;However if the software needs to be modified, the following considerations should be discussed with the appropriate stakeholders (i.e end users, project managers, legal services) and applied to help identify what licences terms and conditions the department is willing to approve.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Are there any reasons that would prevent the release of the modified source code?&#xD;&#xA;No: Subject to the considerations above, you can accept any OSI approved licence or FSF free software licence. See Use Open Source Software With Modifications.&#xD;&#xA;Yes: See 2.&#xD;&#xA;Is the modified application going to be used as a web application?&#xD;&#xA;Yes: Subject to the considerations above, you can accept any OSI approved licence or FSF free software licence except strong reciprocal licences. See Strong Reciprocal Licences.&#xD;&#xA;No: See 3.&#xD;&#xA;Is the modified application going to be distributed externally, outside the GC, either the source code or the binary?&#xD;&#xA;No: Subject to the considerations above, you can accept any OSI approved licence or FSF free software licence.&#xD;&#xA;Yes: Subject to the considerations above, you can accept any OSI approved licence or FSF free software licence except Reciprocal Licences. Use only Permissive Licences.&#xD;&#xA;Additional consultation with legal and engineering teams should be done for scenarios where the open source software is used as a component of custom development (e.g.: dynamic vs static linking, etc.) to ensure licence compatibility.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Popular and Widely Used Licences&#xD;&#xA;The following are lists of licences categorized by permissive and reciprocal. For full list refer to Open Source Initiative (OSI) and Free Software Foundation (FSF) Websites.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Permissive Licences&#xD;&#xA;Apache License&#xD;&#xA;BSD license&#xD;&#xA;ISC License&#xD;&#xA;MIT license&#xD;&#xA;Reciprocal Licences&#xD;&#xA;Eclipse Public License (EPL)&#xD;&#xA;European Union Public License (EUPL)&#xD;&#xA;GNU General Public Licenses (GPL, LGPL and AGPL)&#xD;&#xA;Mozilla Public License (MPL)&#xD;&#xA;Open Software License (OSL)"/>
